<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Shuffling Bytes | Valtteri Lehtinen</title>
    <link>https://shufflingbytes.com/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Shuffling Bytes | Valtteri Lehtinen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2022, Valtteri Lehtinen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 16:16:31 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shufflingbytes.com/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DNS records of 1% .fi domains exposed through Zone Transfers</title>
      <link>https://shufflingbytes.com/posts/zone-trasfer-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 16:16:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shufflingbytes.com/posts/zone-trasfer-experiment/</guid>
      <description>DNS records of 1% .fi domains exposed through Zone Transfers DNS Zone Transfer is a mechanism for administrators to replicate DNS datasets across DNS servers. If it is enabled for a DNS nameserver, the nameserver will gladly give all DNS data regarding a domain to anyone who asks. Enabling Zone Transfers will cause an information disclosure and can thus be considered misconfiguration.
I decided to investigate how common this nameserver misconfiguration is by doing a zone transfer query on all .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I made 56874 calls to explore the telephone network. Here&#39;s what I found</title>
      <link>https://shufflingbytes.com/posts/wardialing-finnish-freephones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 11:06:16 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shufflingbytes.com/posts/wardialing-finnish-freephones/</guid>
      <description>I made 56874 calls to explore the telephone network. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found.  What kind of systems are there in the Finnish telephone network today?
 This question appeared to me a while ago when leafing through an old telephone directory from the early 2000s.
There are at least ordinary subscribers, business customer support lines, voice mails, and fax machines. Subscribers and customer support lines are not of special interest to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned of the VOIP hacker scene by setting up a SIP Honeypot</title>
      <link>https://shufflingbytes.com/posts/sip-honeypot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 18:58:44 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shufflingbytes.com/posts/sip-honeypot/</guid>
      <description>What I learned of the VOIP hacker scene by setting up a SIP Honeypot I got interested in telephones and the Voice Over IP (VOIP) scene soon after reading Phil Lapsley&amp;rsquo;s Exploding the phone (2013). According to the book, there is a whole underground of VOIP hackers. I had not come across them while lurking in the information security scene. After my interest sparked, I started paying more attention to telephone-related security research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
